LaKeisha Williams

Experience Accounting/Bookkeeping Professional

Redford, MI 48239 lakeishawilliams245_ypr@indeedemail.com 3133540854

Seeks an Assistant Controller or Bookkeeping/Management role where I can work independently as a contractor or as a team player to apply my analytical skills and computer knowledge to meet organizational goals.

#readytowork

Willing to relocate to: Chicago, IL - New York, NY - Detroit, MI Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Bookkeeper

Daily Solutions (Self-employed) - Detroit, MI 2012 to Present

Client list includes: Accountants, Artist, Bar, Beauticians, Construction, Food Demonstrator, Home Health Care, IT Consultant, Landscaper, Manufacturer, Not-for-Profit, Used car Dealership, and Restaurants

Performed General Bookkeeping duties for variety of small businesses remote or client's site. Set-up and/or maintain QuickBooks files to ensure efficient work flow and accuracy of accounting activities.

- Executed bookkeeping duties dependent on client specifications including but not limited to: Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable, Check Writing, Invoicing, Bank & Credit Card Account Reconciliations, and posted Journal Entries
- Assisted in payroll, payroll tax filings, payroll year-end processing, sales tax computation & filing and income tax preparations. Processed, compiled and prepared month-end and year-end financial reports and other standard reporting requirements.
- Identified work flow issues and implement procedures to streamline processes and increase efficiency and productivity
- Interacted with accountant on as needed basis to communicate financial reporting for quarter and vear-end tax needs
- Produced and reviewed Financial Reports as requested
- Created and/or upheld efficient filing system for all clients as needed
- Worked on small projects including: setting up QuickBooks file and chart of accounts, correcting incorrect entries, year-end clean up and quarterly transaction entry
- Built strong relationships with clients to gain their trust with financial affairs

Controller/Accounting Manager

Metro Solutions - Southfield, MI January 2017 to June 2018

- > Manager: Created human resource forms, oversaw and trained staff on various payroll procedures for QuickBooks & tax agencies as well as documented company accounting procedures; managed workload amongst the team to meet tax deadlines
- > Accounting: Compiled data for 400+ household payroll clients using (1) QuickBooks master file; Created and posted general/standard journal entries to the general ledger through Trial Balance; generated internal financial statements for Management, maintain Fixed Assets for Depreciation & Insurance; handled month-end, worked closely with external CPA with accounting issues and questions; and worked with auditors for annual audits
- > Banking: Reconciled four bank and credit card accounts, dealt with account activity discrepancies, and prepare bank deposits
- > Accounts Receivables: Created, posted, and e-mail invoices; monitored open invoices, applied customer check and EFT payments to open invoices
- > Accounts Payables: Coded & entered bills for payment, disbursed weekly bill payments, and process 1099-MISCs
- > Payroll: Prepared and submitted payroll via 3rd party payroll agency online, posted after the fact processed payroll in QuickBooks, balanced monthly employee liability & employer expense general ledger accounts to 3rd party payroll agency payroll journals

Finance Associate & Bookkeeper

Barkley Kalpak Agency (now First Agency) - New York, NY July 2010 to January 2017

- > Accounting: Created and posted general/standard journal entries to the general ledger through Trial Balance; generated internal financial statements for Management, maintained Fixed Assets for Depreciation & Insurance; handled month-end, prepared backup for quarterly sales tax returns, and work closely with external CPA with accounting issues and questions
- > Banking: Reconciled general ledger accounts to bank statements and credit card statements; and prepared bank deposits
- > Accounts Receivables: Created, posted, and e-mailed invoices; monitored open invoices, applied customer credit card & check payments, and handled Collections via e-mail or fax
- > Accounts Payables: Coded & entered bills for payment, disbursed weekly bill payments, and processed 1099-MISCs
- > Payroll: Prepared and submitted payroll via Paychex online, posted after the fact processed payroll in QuickBooks, balanced monthly employee liability & employer expense general ledger accounts to Paychex payroll journals
- > Human Resources: Handled New Hire forms, yearly audits, and maintained employee files

Bookkeeper

The Bonadio Group - Pittsford, NY November 2007 to June 2010

- > Client Services & Accounting: Provided QuickBooks training to clients, provided bookkeeping services (Write-ups) that included bank reconciliations, maintained fixed assets, reconciled general ledger accounts through Trial Balance to prepare monthly and quarterly compilations along with tick marking work papers to reflect g/l accounts in a paperless environment for clients
- > Taxes: Prepared corporate tax returns and NY Sales Tax Returns for various clients

Education

Associate in Accounting Information Management

Davenport University - Grand Rapids, MI

September 2011 to April 2013

Some college

Skills

- Quickbooks (10+ years)
- Tax Preparation
- Reconciliation (10+ years)
- General Ledger (10+ years)
- Accounts Payable (10+ years)
- Accounts Receivable (10+ years)
- Payroll (10+ years)
- Financial Statements (10+ years)
- 10-Key (10+ years)
- Excel (10+ years)
- Word (10+ years)
- QuickBooks Online (2 years)
- Bookkeeping
- Microsoft Excel
- Outlook
- accounting
- Billing
- Budgeting
- Receptionist
- Account Reconciliation
- Balance Sheet Reconciliation
- · Bank Reconciliation
- Financial Report Writing
- General Ledger Reconciliation
- Journal Entries
- Office Management
- Data Entry
- Financial Statement Preparation

Certifications and Licenses

NACPB

December 2018 to Present

Assessments

Accounting Skills: Bookkeeping — Expert

January 2020

Calculating and determining the accuracy of financial data.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share to profile/

fd094cb3a36b53cd414ea3f65adad14deed53dc074545cb7

Accounting Skills: Bookkeeping — Expert

December 2019

Calculating and determining the accuracy of financial data.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share to profile/

a2a1b91850837c07addb2b0cae03fd4eeed53dc074545cb7

Principles of Accounting — Highly Proficient

December 2019

Preparing financial records according to federal policies.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/3cf1f8a2f488fe4282bad18e8d119296eed53dc074545cb7

Office Manager — Proficient

December 2019

Scheduling and budgeting.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/689f07eda5b0805727e64d85ff5d827ceed53dc074545cb7

Attention to Detail — Proficient

December 2019

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/3462f6f07b880e64aa2b3f35ec5b715ceed53dc074545cb7

Reliability — Highly Proficient

December 2019

Tendency to be dependable and come to work.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_to_profile/

c205e0cc15c6bafdd1f60ca0b3e9d45ceed53dc074545cb7

Accounting Skills: Basic Principles — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to prepare financial records according to federal policies.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

<u>share to profile/7102c87a4b32614fcccb751b19fc2b82eed53dc074545cb7</u>

Data Entry — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Entering data quickly and accurately.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/00ec6abd23e02846dd52a0dc28cb8638eed53dc074545cb7

Accounting Skills: Bookkeeping — Expert

November 2018

Measures a candidate's ability to calculate and determine the accuracy of financial data.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

<u>share to profile/3948fd4ce574c8cdda63041622647a2beed53dc074545cb7</u>

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.